Toyoaki Uehara papers, 1945-1990 C611
Indiana University Archives
Toyoaki Uehara papers
1945-1990
Indiana University Archives
Uehara, Toyoaki
C611
15.4 cubic feet 16 boxes
Toyoaki Uehara (1924-1997) was a professor in the Department of East Asian Languages and Cultures at Indiana University Bloomington from 1963-1990. This collection documents Uehara's scholarly career and personal life, including his participation on university and departmental committees, research and publications related to Japanese language, literature, and mythology; development of international exchange programs; and his involvement in the Tenrikyo movement. Types of material include departmental documents, minutes and memos, program enrollment figures, research and grant proposals, and business correspondence. Also included are copies of Uehara's dissertation, publications and research materials, lectures, bibliographies, extensive personal correspondence, and paper and audiovisual Japanese language study and instruction materials.
Access Restrictions
The files transferred to Box 9 are closed to researchers due to the presence of Social Security numbers. With prior notification for review, Archives staff may be able to make these available to researchers.
Advance notice required for access to the collection.
Biographical Note
Toyoaki Uehara was born November 9th, 1924 in Okayama, Japan. He worked as a teaching assistant at Tenri University in Tenri, Japan from 1950-1951 and was heavily involved in the Tenrikyo movement that established the university. After moving to the United States he worked as an instructor in the Army's Defense Language Institute from 1954-1956. He then moved to Los Angeles on a scholarship, earning his Ph.D. in Religion with a minor in Asian Studies in 1960 at the University of Southern California, where he later lectured. After two years as assistant professor at Seton Hall University in New Jersey, Uehara was hired as an assistant professor in the Department of East Asian Languages and Literature (later East Asian Languages and Cultures) at Indiana University, Bloomington, in 1963, becoming a full professor in 1984.He retired in 1990 with the title Professor Emeritus of East Asian Languages and Cultures.
While at I.U., Uehara coordinated the Tenri University student and faculty exchange programs from 1966 until 1989 as well as several additional Asian exchange programs from various institutions including United College in Hong Kong. He was an active member of numerous committees that enabled foreign language workshops, summer institutes, and campus courses to flourish. He collaborated in the authorship of several books and monographs, the most well-known being Fundamentals of Japanese, co-written with Gisaburo N. Kiyose and published by Indiana University Press in 1975, which became the primary Japanese language textbook of its time. He also translated a number of materials between English and Japanese and compiled comprehensive bibliographies of relevant language and religious materials with the assistance of various colleagues.
Uehara continued to work as a consultant with Tenri University after retiring from I.U., traveling and maintaining his correspondence with former students and colleagues around the world. He passed away March 4, 1997. The IU Department of East Asian Languages and Literatures offers annual Uehara scholarships to undergraduate showing excellence in East Asian studies, named in honor of the late professor.
Arrangement
Collection is organized into seven series: Subject Files, Writings, Language Materials, Audiovisual Materials, Electronic Media, Administrative Files, and Correspondence.
Scope and Content Note
This collection documents Uehara's activities as a member of the East Asian Languages and Cultures faculty at Indiana University, Bloomington, including his participation on university and departmental committees, research and publications related to Japanese language, literature, and mythology; and development of international exchange programs. Also documented are Uehara's relationships with Japanese and American scholars, including colleagues, former students and exchange program participants, and Tenri University faculty; his interest in the Tenrikyo movement; and his personal life.
Types of material present in the collection include reports, syllabi and other course materials, language drills and flashcards, evaluations, meeting agendas and minutes, memoranda, conference materials, newsletters, audio recordings; curricula vitae, research notes and publications, professional and personal correspondence, electronic documents, and newspaper clippings.
Individuals represented in the collection include Kiyoko Uehara, Osamu Uehara, Shuko Kobayashi, Kikuo Tanaka, Yu Ju Chih, Floyd Ross, Peter Metevelis, and Milton "Milt" Critchfield.
Separated Material
All photographs have been pulled from Correspondence and Writings files and housed with the Indiana University Photograph Collection, with copies of corresponding papers and envelopes.
Related Material
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database
Acquisition Information
2015/106
Provenance
Gift of Osamu Uehara, 2015.
Appraisal
- Résumés, applications, letters of recommendation, proficiency scores, grades, and private material regarding third parties have been removed and shredded.
- 3.5" floppy discs (88), mostly copies of software and utilities programs for Macintosh computers, have been removed.
- 47 videotapes of copies of Japanese television shows and two VHS 2-drawer storage cabinets have been removed.
- 20 analog audio tapes of a variety of Japanese harp and flute music and a recording of Faust, have been removed.
- 1 undated photograph mounted on wooden frame with taped edges, enclosed in a paper sleeve, of Tenrikyo Temple (16 1/2 x 23 1/2 x 3/4 inches) has been removed due to damage and preservation issues.
- Where possible, the original order of the files has been retained, which has left Uehara's personal papers comingled with departmental records.
Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of East Asian Languages and Cultures--Faculty--Archives.; Japanese language--Study and teaching (Higher)--Indiana--Bloomington--History--Sources.; Japanese teachers--Indiana--Bloomington--History--Sources.; Records (Documents); Business correspondence.; Uehara, Toyoaki -- Archives; Uehara, Toyoaki -- Correspondence
- Subject Files, 1950-1990 (Box 1)
  Scope and Content Note
  This series includes some research and publication materials, as well as employment and education information, newspaper clippings, and some intermixed personal and professional correspondence.
  Arrangement
  The files are arranged in rough alphabetical order, then in reverse chronological order where years have been provided.
  - Association for Asian Studies, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Association for Japanese Language Teachers, 1968 and undated (Box 1)
  - Andrew Chang Textbook, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Computer Software Program, undated (Box 1)
  - Copyright, 1972 and undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1968 and undated (Box 1)
    - Universities, Organizations (Box 1)
    - Personal (Box 1)
  - Employment (Box 1)
    - University of Michigan, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - Seton Hall University, 1960-1964 (Box 1)
    - Tenri University, 1990, 1992 and undated (Box 1)
    - University of So. Calif., 1956-1958 (Box 1)
  - Indiana University (Box 1)
    - I.U.P.U.I., 1981-1985 (Box 1)
    - Ph. D. Candidacy Qualifying Examination, 1956-1960 (Box 1)
    - Study at Univ. of So. Calif. (for M.A.), 1950-1954 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Report, 1965-1989 and undated (Box 1)
    - Research Proposals, Faculty Reports, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Sabbatical Leave, 1970-1986 (Box 1)
    - Curriculum Vitae (Box 1)
      - 1984, 1987 (Box 1)
      - 1963-1983 (Box 1)
  - Fundamentals of Japanese (Box 1)
    - 1978-1983 and undated (Box 1)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 1)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 1)
  - [Label in Japanese], Materials in Support of Service, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Prof. S. Hisamatsu, undated (Box 1)
  - Hitler, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Immigration Documents (Box 1)
    - 1990-1992 (Box 1)
    - Trip to Japan, June 12-November 6,1958 (Box 1)
  - Invitation to the Inauguration of President G.W. Bush for President of U.S.A., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Japanese Consulate General, 1961-1987 (Box 2)
  - Japanese Crown Prince, 1960-1989 (Box 2)
  - Japanese Language School, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Lectures (Shinto, Buddhism, etc.), 1951-1987 (Box 2)
    - Teaching Japanese Presentation, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Japanese Student Club at U.S.C., 1958-1959 (Box 2)
    - Japanese American Junior Chamber of Commerce, 1960-1961 and undated (Box 2)
    - Well Wishes Booklet, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Post War Shinto, 1962, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Public Lecture, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Museum of the American Indian, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Leon Zolbrod, 1655-1966 (Box 2)
  - Letter of Support (for Sachio), June 1959 (Box 2)
  - Tenri University Library, undated (Box 2)
  - Tenri Exchange, 1983-1990 (Box 2)
  - IU-Tenri Exchange, July-October, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Promotion, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
    Conditions Governing Access
    (Restricted)
  - Exchange Program with Tenri, 1966-1986 (Box 2)
    - 1981-1986 (Box 2)
    - 1966-1980, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - 1966-1980 (Box 2)
  - Exchange Program for Faculty with Tenri University, 1971-1981 (Box 2)
  - Exchange Program, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Exchange-United College-Hong Kong, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Exchange Books Tenri University, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Exchange Program with Kyoto University, 1966-1969 (Box 2)
  - Exchange Program for Student United College & Tenri University, 1966-1979 (Box 2)
  - Student Exchange Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Professor Uehara Student Exchange Committee Information, 1977 (Box 2)
- Writings, 1960-1973 (Box 2)
  Writings consist of two subseries: one containing the research, drafts, and final copies of writings authored by Uehara (published and unpublished), including copies of his dissertations; and a second subseries of collected writings. Some Japanese newspapers are also included with these materials.
  - Authored by Uehara, circa 1960s
    - Dissertation, undated (Box 2)
      - Appendix (Box 2)
      - Glossary (Box 2)
      - Bibliography (Box 2)
      - Conclusion (Box 2)
      - Chapt. VII (Box 2)
      - Chapt. VI (Box 3)
      - Chapt. V (Box 3)
      - Chapt. IV (Box 3)
      - Chapt. III (Box 3)
      - Chapt. II (Box 3)
      - Chapt. I (Box 3)
      - Introduction (Box 3)
    - Dissertation The Dynamics of the Archetypes in Japanese Shinto Mythology, 1960 (Box 3)
      - Chapts. V-VIII, Appendix A, B, C (Box 3)
      - Intro, Chapts. I-IV (2nd draft) (Box 3)
    - The Dynamics of the Archetypes in Japanese Shinto Mythology (bound edited copy), 1960 (Box 3)
    - Dissertation Seminar, 1968 (Box 3)
    - The Dynamics of the Archetypes in Japanese Shinto Mythology (bound dissertation), 1960 (Box 3)
    - A Study of Tenrikyo (bound thesis), 1955 (Box 3)
    - Fundamentals of Japanese (bound copy), 1974 (Box 3)
    - Tenrikyo Teaching of God and Man, 1953 (Box 3)
      - Introduction, Chapts. 1-2 (Box 3)
        Separated Material
        26 photographs from this folder have been transferred to the IU Archives Photograph Collection. Contact the Archives Photograph Curator for more information.
      - Chapts. 3-5 (Box 3)
      - Chapts. 6-8, Bibliography, Appendix A (Box 4)
    - Thesis notecards, undated (Box 4)
    - Christianity and Civilization manuscript, 1951; (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Ofudesaki, undated (Box 4)
    - [Notes and clippings in Japanese], undated (Box 4)
    - Mikagurauta, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Shinto Myth Pub., 1981-1986 (Box 4)
    - First Draft Shinto Myth I-IV, undated (Box 4)
    - The Shinto Myth: Meaning, Symbolism, and Individuation, Original I-V, undated (Box 4)
    - Encyclopedia of Religion Pub., 1986-1987 (Box 4)
    - Encyclopedia of Japan Pub., 1978 (Box 4)
    - Fundamentals of Japanese comments, 1968-1969 and undated (Box 4)
    - Drill Text for Fundamentals of Japanese, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Fundamentals of Japanese manuscript, 1974; (4 folders) (Box 5)
    - Mohammed, the Hero of the Islamic Consciousness, 1975, undated; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Introduction to Phonology, Orthography, and Grammar of the Japanese Language, 1968 (Box 5)
    - [Label in Japanese] Pub., 1972 (Box 5)
    - Bhagavad Gita, a Key to Salvation through the Reintegration of the Self, 1972 (Box 5)
    - Image of Man in Creation, 1966 (Box 5)
    - Journalistic Japanese, 1962 (Box 5)
    - Postwar Shinto, 1962 (Box 5)
    - Tenrikyo (4 Articles), 1956-1958 (Box 5)
    - The Significant Characteristics of Shinto in Historical Development, 1956 (Box 5)
    - Study on Rise of Sectarian Shintoism, 1952 (Box 5)
    - On Inevitable Process of Kant's Concept of God as a Postulate, 1952 (Box 5)
    - The Problem of Absolute Other Power in Faith of Shinran, 1952 (Box 5)
    - Notes on Four Books: History of Christian Thought, 1952 (Box 5)
    - Comparison of God Concept, 1952 (Box 5)
    - On Taoism, 1952 (Box 5)
    - Problem of Pauline Thought, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Christian Love, 1951 (Box 5)
    - The Children of Light and the Children of Darkness, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Love, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Social Salvation, 1951 (Box 5)
    - The Protestant Ethic and the Spirit of Capitalism, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Christianity and Civilization, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Christian Ethic and Social Policy, 1951 (Box 5)
    - The Common Man's Philosophy, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Reading Notes, 1958 (Box 5)
    - The Bhagavad Gita as a Teaching of Non-Self Practice, 1958 (Box 5)
    - The Growth of the Islamic mind in the Light of Psycho Evolutionary Theory, 1957 (Box 5)
    - Development of the Racial Psyche in Relation to Japanese Shinto Mythology, 1957 (Box 5)
    - The Fundamental Teaching of the Bhagavad Gita, 1957 (Box 5)
    - Mikagurauta, an English Translation in Original Meter (author's copy), 1987 (Box 5)
    - [Notes and Papers in English and Japanese], 1958; and undated; (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - [Materials in Japanese], undated (Box 6)
  - Collected Writings, 1956-1982 (Box 6)
    - Various Edited Text Fragments, undated (Box 6)
    - Bibliography by Sakakura, undated (Box 6)
    - Kanbun, undated (Box 6)
    - Kanji Chronology, undated (Box 6)
    - Oriental Philosophy (Chinese), 1956 and undated (Box 6)
    - Philosophical Text, undated (Box 6)
    - Buddhism, undated (Box 6)
    - Bibliography Materials by Dr. Ross, 1956-1957 and undated (Box 6)
    - Suwaritsutome, undated (Box 6)
    - Tenri Journal of Religion, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - Number 15, 1981 (Box 6)
    - Number 16, 1982 (Box 6)
- Language Materials, 1945-1977 (Box 6)
  This series consists of language course resources such as drills and flashcards, and bound and unbound Language Institute papers. Also included is a copy of the Military Intelligence Service Language School (M.I.S.L.S.) album, which was presented to Uehara in 1956, commemorating the history of the school, its linguists, and the graduates who gave their lives during World War II. Printed language drills may have associated audio recordings located in the Audiovisual Materials series.
  - Advanced Japanese Conversation, 1961-1963 (Box 6)
  - Chinese language flashcards, undated (Box 6)
  - Papers of the C.I.C. Far Eastern Language Institute, Volume IV, 1968-1970 (Box 6)
  - Japanese Grammar, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Jap. Teaching Material, undated (Box 6)
  - Official Translation of the Japanese Constitution, undated (Box 6)
  - Japanese, Basic Course, Volume II, Lessons 7-18, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Japanese, Basic Course, Volume III, Lessons 19-24, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Japanese, Sounds of Japanese Speech, Volume I, undated (Box 6)
  - Carnegie Summer Institute of Japanese documentation, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Kanji and Compounds Primer and Reader I Arranged Alphabetically, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Oral Drill Text based on Naganuma Primer, 1951 (Box 6)
  - Japanese Songs, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Japanese Particles, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Derivations of 300 Kanji in Revised Naganuma Primer and Reader I, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Japanese Verbs, 1955 (Box 6)
  - [Japanese vocabulary supplement], undated (Box 6)
  - Classroom Expressions and Introductory Conversation, 1951 (Box 6)
  - Japanese Movie Synopses, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Japanese Proverbs, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Yearbook of Military Intelligence Service Language School (MISLS) The MISLS Album, 1945-1946 (Box 6)
  - NDEA Institute for Japanese Language, 1964 and 1966 (Box 6)
  - Carnegie Japanese Language Institute Final Report, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Final Report on the National Defense Education Act, East Coast Consortium, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Final Report on the National Defense Language Institute for Elementary and Secondary Teachers of Chinese, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Japanese Teaching Materials, undated (Box 7)
  - A Key to Level of Speech in Japanese, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Advanced Japanese Grammar, undated (Box 7)
  - Japanese Teaching Material (Family Relation Chart), undated (Box 7)
  - Japanese Letter Writing, undated (Box 7)
  - Japanese Language Study in U.S.A., 1972 (Box 7)
  - Intensive Pattern Drill Test, Vols. I and II, undated (Box 7)
  - Advanced Japanese Conversation, 1961-1963 (Box 7)
- Audiovisual materials, circa 1950s-1960s and undated (Box 8)
  The Audiovisual Materials series consist of 58 open reel audio tapes and 19 analog audio cassette tapes. They are mostly Japanese language drills, with some lectures, music, and unlabeled items. Related print materials are located in the Language Materials series.
  - Bill Stanley Piano Sonata, undated; 7" Scotch 190 acetate; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - [title in Japanese]Claremont, Calif., September 15, 1957; 7" Scotch 190 acetate; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - Jorden, undated; 7" Dupont Magnetic Recording Tape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - Jorden, Beginning Japanese Vol. 1, undated; 7" Dupont Magnetic Recording Tape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
    - #1 - #5, (5 tapes) (Box 8)
  - Jorden, Beginning Japanese Vol. 2, undated; 7" Dupont Magnetic Recording Tape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
    - #1 - #5, (5 tapes) (Box 8)
  - Japanese Pronunciation (Accents) "The Tones of Japanese", undated; 7" Dupont Magnetic Recording Tape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - Han, Modern Japanese, undated; 7" Dupont Magnetic Recording Tape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
    - #1, Lessons 1-5 (Box 8)
    - #2, Lessons 6-9 (Box 8)
    - #3, Lessons 10-12 (Box 8)
  - Han, Public Lecture on Japanese Pronunciation, undated; 7" Dupont Magnetic Recording Tape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - Uehara, Advanced Japanese Conversation, undated; 7" Dupont Magnetic Recording Tape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
    - #1, Lessons 1-6 (Box 8)
    - #2, Lessons 7-9 (Box 8)
    - #3, Lessons 10-12 (Box 8)
    - #4, Lessons 13-14 (Box 8)
  - Uehara's Journalistic Japanese Reader, undated; 7" Dupont Magnetic Recording Tape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
    - #1 - #5, (5 tapes) (Box 8)
  - Uehara's Journalistic Japanese Reader Fast Reading, undated; 7" Dupont Magnetic Recording Tape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
    - #1 - #3, (3 tapes) (Box 8)
  - Jorden, Beginning Japanese Vol. 1 #6, undated; 5" Dupont Magnetic Recording Tape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - Teichiku Military Music of Japan, June 1, 1969; 7" Scotch 150 polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - [title in Japanese] Koto Shakuhachi (Japanese Harp), undated; 7" Scotch 111 acetate; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - Hyojun Nippongo Tokuhon, Jap. 201, June 1, 1965; 7" Sarkes Tarzian 1131-12 acetate; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
    - Volume 1-Part 1 (Box 8)
    - Lessons 24-43 (Box 8)
    - Lessons 44-50 (Box 8)
  - Japanese Drills - Uehara Drills, June 2, 1965; 7" Sarkes Tarzian 1131-12 acetate; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
    - 1-18 (Box 8)
    - 19-35 (Box 8)
    - 36-50 (Box 8)
  - Japanese, October 15, 1965; 7" Sarkes Tarzian 1131-12 acetate; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - Japanese Naganuma Reader Intensive Pattern Drills, undated; 7" Sarkes Tarzian 1131-12 acetate; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
    - Lessons 1-5 (Box 8)
    - Lessons 6-11 (Box 8)
    - Lessons 12-17 (Box 8)
    - Lessons 18-23 (Box 8)
    - Lessons 24-28 (Box 8)
  - Japanese Naganuma Reader Intensive Pattern Drills Lessons 29-30, undated; 7" Ampex 631 polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - [title in Japanese], S. Kenmore, L.A., undated; 7" Fedcal acetate; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - untitled (possibly blank), undated; 5" Scotch 211 polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - untitled (possibly blank), undated; 5" Soni-Tape acetate; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 8)
  - Uehara Drill, Nag. Bk 1, Pt. 2, undated; 7" Dressner Audio Sales Co. Meritape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 9)
    - Les. 6-11 (Box 9)
    - Les. 18-22 (Box 9)
    - Les. 28-30 (Box 9)
  - Uehara Drill, Nag. Bk 2, undated; 7" Dressner Audio Sales Co. Meritape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 9)
    General
    (canister may not be correctly labeled)
    - Les. 1-10 (Box 9)
    - Less 11- (Box 9)
  - Uehara Tape I, Intensive Pattern Drill Les. 1-15, undated; 7" Dressner Audio Sales Co. Meritape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 9)
  - Uehara Tape II, Intensive Pattern Drill Les. 40-50, undated; 7" Dressner Audio Sales Co. Meritape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 9)
  - Untitled, undated; 7" Dressner Audio Sales Co. Meritape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 9)
  - Untitled (possibly blank), undated; 7" Dressner Audio Sales Co. Meritape polyester; genreform: ¼" analog audio open reel tape (Box 9)
  - Empty reel in plastic canister (Box 9)
  - Uehara & Kiyose, Fundamentals of Japanese, undated; Scotch C-90 Type 1 analog audio cassette tape (Box 9)
    - #1 Lesson I (Box 9)
    - #2 Lesson II-III (Box 9)
    - #3 Lesson IV-V (Box 9)
    - #4 Lesson VI-VII (Box 9)
    - #5 Lesson VIII-IX (Box 9)
    - #6 Lesson X-XI (Box 9)
    - #7 Lesson XII-XIII (Box 9)
    - #8 Lesson XIV-XV (Box 9)
    - #9 Lesson XI-XVII (Box 9)
    - #10 Lesson XVIII-XIX (Box 9)
    - #11 Lesson XX-XXI (Box 9)
    - #12 Lesson XXII-XXIII (Box 9)
    - #13 Lesson XXIV-XXV (Box 9)
    - #14 Lesson XXVI (Box 9)
  - First Level, Less 1-21, undated; Sony LNX90 Type 1 analog audio cassette tape (Box 9)
  - Second Level, Less 1-24, undated; Sony LNX90 Type 1 analog audio cassette tape (Box 9)
  - Chinese Tone, undated; Sony LNX90 Type 1 analog audio cassette tape (Box 9)
  - Beginning Mandarin Chinese, T. Richard Chi, Less 22-Less, undated; Unidentified Son Type 1 analog audio cassette tape (Box 9)
  - J101 (78) Speech at the End of Semester, undated; Sony C-60 Chrome Type 2 analog audio cassette tape (Box 9)
- Electronic media, circa 1990s and undated; 21; genreform: 3½" floppy disks (Box 9)
  This series includes documents relating to publications including Shinto Myth and various other writings, Fundamentals of Japanese drills, Indiana University matters, additional notes, and copies of Uehara's curriculum vitae.
  Access Note
  Electronic materials require additional processing before they can be accessed. Please contact the Archives staff for further information.
  - Ofudesaki Part 3 copied from Internal, June 29, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Ofudesaki Word Perfect, undated (Box 9)
  - IBM MS-DOS Ofudesaki, undated (Box 9)